Guide to the Martin Gardner Papers SC0647
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Subject files, Series 2
  - Macmahon's Color Polygons, 4 folder(s)
    - Corner-Color Squares (Nitty-Gritty, Odier, etc), 1970-1984 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      Zimmerman, J.J.
    - Corner-Color Trangles (Odier), 1959-1975 (Box 27, Folder 2)
      La Trioker
      Patent applications for Marc Odier games.
      Also various other related patents.
    - Macmahon Color Hexagons, 1971-1978 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      Sets of hexagons to make edge-matched shapes, by L. Vossburgh Lyons, by Leslie Shader (XIX & CXX), and "Drive You Nuts".
      Notes on Voz (L. Vosburgh Lyons) after his death.
      Prichodjko, Alexander
      Lyons, L. Vossburgh (Voz)
    - 3D Forms, undated (Box 27, Folder 4)
      Several edge matching 3D puzzles.
  - Magic Squares, Etc., 23 folder(s)
    - Magic Squares - History and General [1 of 2], 1953-1976 (Box 56, Folder 4)
      "Fantasies in Figures, Mathematic Mysteries and Magic Squares", in Treasury of Folklore, by "Meloc" (Stanley Jackson Coleman), 1956 (mimeograph booklet)
      "Report on Considerations Concerning Magic Squares and Their Use in Digital Design", by J.H. White, 38pp (mimeo, stapled)
      Laposky, Ben
      Helbing, Edgar
    - Magic Squares - History and General [2 of 2], 1983-2000 (Box 56, Folder 5)
      More notes, letters and articles on magic squares
    - Order-3 Square, 1958-2001 (Box 56, Folder 6)
      Puzzles based on order-3 squares
      Articles, analyses, etc
    - Anti-Magic Squares, 1965-1971 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Order-4 Square (Diabolic), 1938-1998 (Box 56, Folder 8)
      Pandiagonal magic squares (by Ollerenshaw)
    - Durer's Melancholia, undated (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Magic Square Magic Tricks, 1942-1997 (Box 56, Folder 10)
      The Magic Square, Bert Allerton (simplified version, 1942)
      The Magic Square, Phil Burns, 1956
      Birthday Magic Squares, Max Katz, 1962
      Patterns of Perfection, Sam Dalal, 1993
      Some Stewart James predictions
      The Ultimate Magic Square, by Christoph Wasshuber (Chris the Magician)
    - The Order-5 Square, 1962-1975 (Box 56, Folder 11)
      Program for counting order 5 magic squares: Bill Gosper, Richard Schroeppel, Michael Beeler, 1973
    - Orders > 5 (Squares), 1963-1997 (Box 57, Folder 1)
      Franklin's Square
      Pandiagonal Magic Squares of the Seventh Order (mimeo)
      Other algorithms
    - The 32x32 Trimagic Square, 1973-1976 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Material on it by William H. Benson
      Madachy, Joseph
    - Magic Stellated Dodecahedron, 1976 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      "Whitchcraft, or Perfect Magic Icosapentacles", by Bayard Wynne, 19pp (typescript)
      Wynne calls the small stellated dodecahedron "Icosapentacles"
    - Magic Graphs, 1964-1980 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Magic Octagons (French)
      Various shapes and structures
    - Antimagic Triangles & Other Forms, 1980-1981 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      3 articles by Charles Trigg (typescript)
    - Ennumeration of 6, 7, & 8, 1966-1988 (Box 57, Folder 6)
      Domergue, A.
      Moldon, Alan
      Montgomery, Coralie
      Ulrich, E.J.
      Seare, S.A.
    - Sallows' Complex 3x3 Squares, 1996-1997 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Magic Triangles, 1957-1992 (Box 57, Folder 8)
      Piersel, W.Guthrie
    - Alphamagic (Lee Sallows), 1986-1997 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Magic Hexagons (Aug/63), 1924-1992 (Box 57, Folder 10)
      Much reader correspondance
      Only 3rd order magic hexagons exist: proof
      Magic Hexagon Puzzle - (in 3D box)
      Tapson, Frank
      Adams, Clifford
      Fabel, Karl
    - Magic Rectangles, 1998-2000 (Box 57, Folder 11)
      2 articles by Hadedorn (typescript)
      Summary & chapters from book by Gil Lamb
      Couple of other articles
      Hadedorn, Thomas
    - Other Types, 1966-1994 (Box 57, Folder 12)
      Magic Circles
      The Missing Fifth (magic trick)
      Lyons, Vosburgh (VOZ)
    - Multiplying Squares, 1963-1997 (Box 57, Folder 13)
      McKay, Angus
    - Magic Stars, 1964-2002 (Box 57, Folder 14)
      Graham, Arthur
      Chadosch, Robert
    - Venn Diagrams, 2000 (Box 57, Folder 15)
      Bernardo Recaman on Magic Venn Diagrams
      Recaman, Bernardo
  - Maps, 7 folder(s)
    - 4 Color Conjecture & Equivalents [1 of 2], 1959-1973 (Box 40, Folder 1)
      References
      "Remarks on the Four Color Problem", by Morris E. Rill, 1969, U. of OK. Preprint 94
    - 4 Color Conjecture & Equivalents [2 of 2], 1957-1999 (Box 40, Folder 2)
      Bibliography (from mid-1970's) by Bernhart
      "Origins of Graph Theory - A History to 1900", by P.J. Federico, sections 20-25 (photocopies)
      2 letters to 4-color proovers (that their proofs had mistakes)
    - Map & Set Coloring (Misc), 1957-1996 (Box 40, Folder 3)
      Various articles on coloring maps, 2, 3, & 5 color theorems, etc.
      MG list of map coloring puzzles & games
      Gunlock, Howard
    - Heawood's Conjecture, 1890-1970 (Box 40, Folder 4)
      "Soluotion of the Heawood Map-Coloring Problem", by Gerhard Ringel and J.N.T. Youngs, 1968 (typescript)
    - Spenser-Brown's 4-color "Proof", 1977-1978 (Box 40, Folder 5)
      Work of G. Spenser-Brown
      Some Comments on Alleged Proof by G. Spenser-Brown, by Frank Bernhart
      Scott Kim - analysis of the proof
      David Singmaster letter about Spenser-Brown lecture on his proof
      Spenser-Brown, G.
    - Appel-Haken 1976 Proof of 4-Color Theorem, 1976-1986 (Box 40, Folder 6)
      Several popular and semi-technical articles and announcements about the proof
      Appel, Ken
    - 3-Color Map Problem, 1992-1993 (Box 40, Folder 7)
      Photo of Nat Friedman sculpture with trefoil knot hole
      "The State of the Three Color Problem", by Richard Steinberg, 1992 (typescript)
  - Mathematicians (Alphabetical), 71 folder(s)
    - Adelman, Leonard, 1994 (Box 37, Folder 10)
      1 article
    - Bankoff, Leon, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Ball, W.R.R., undated (Box 37, Folder 12)
      Biography & bibliography, by David Singmasster (typescript)
    - Bell, E.T., 1992-1993 (Box 37, Folder 13)
      Outline, first page, and intro matter of poem "The Scarlet Night"
      Reid, Constance
    - Berlekamp, 1994 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Bennett, Chas., 1987-1992 (Box 37, Folder 15)
      Various articles by Bannett, on Maxwell's Demon, Complexity, etc.
    - Bernoullis, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 16)
      Article, book revies on Bernoulli brothers
    - Bourbaki, 1957-1976 (Box 37, Folder 17)
      Several articles about Bourbaki
      Some references (MG)
    - Cantor, G., 1988-1995 (Box 37, Folder 18)
      Several articles on Cantor
    - Chung, Fan, undated (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - Cipra, Barry, 1997 (Box 37, Folder 20)
      1 short newpaper article
    - Benjamin, Arthur, 1998 (Box 37, Folder 21)
    - Cartwright, Mary, 1999 (Box 37, Folder 22)
    - Clifford, undated (Box 37, Folder 23)
      W.K. Clifford: Life and Philosophy, aobut 52 pjages (typescript), ND, no author
      "The Ethics of Belief", by W.K. Clifford, 5pp (photocopy)
    - Conway, 1970-2001 (Box 37, Folder 24)
      Many magazine and newspaper articles on Conway
      2 long letters from Conway to MG
    - Coxeter, 1985-2001 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Danzig, George, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - De Bruijn, undated (Box 38, Folder 3)
      1 photo
    - Dewdney, Kee, 1986-1987 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Diaconis, Persi, 1977-1990 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Elkies, Noam, 1997-1998 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Erdos, 1969-2000 (Box 38, Folder 7)
      Many interviews with and articles about Erdos
      Reviews of books about Erdos
      Discussions of Erdos number
    - Euler, undated (Box 38, Folder 8)
      Excerpt from book "Euler, The Master of us All", and article by Harary
    - Fisher, Irving, undated (Box 38, Folder 9)
      1 article (book review of his biography, by Robert Allen)
    - Godel [1 of 3], 1962-2000 (Box 38, Folder 10)
      Rotating Universe & Time Travel
      Photocopy of "Godel Meets Einstein", by Palle Yourgrau, Open Court Press, 1999 (252 pages)
      Some articles on Godels incompleteness theorem
    - Godel [2 of 3], 1954-1996 (Box 38, Folder 11)
      Articles on Godel's imcompleteness theorem
      MG notes on Godel's proof
      Some biographical articles
    - Godel [3 of 3], 1964-2000 (Box 38, Folder 12)
      Several articles by Has Wang (a friend of Godel) on Godel
      Several biographical articles
      Articles about ideas stemming from Godel, and the Foundations of Mathematics
    - Goldberg, Michael, 1990 (Box 38, Folder 13)
      Letter from his son, Jefemy, plus short biography
    - Golomb, 1996-2000 (Box 38, Folder 14)
      Solomon golomb
      USC article on Golomb's appointment ot Viterbi Chair in Communications
      Golomb articles on Mathematics 40 years after Sputnik
      Golomb, Beatrice
    - Gosper, 1995 (Box 38, Folder 15)
      William Gosper
      Letter from MG recommending Gosper for MacArthur Fellowship
    - Ron & NFan Graham, 1981-1997 (Box 38, Folder 16)
      Several articles on Ron Graham, one on Fan Chung Graham
    - Guy, Berlekamp, Selfridge, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 17)
      2 photos of the 3 of them, plus interview with Guy
    - Halmos, 1980-1985 (Box 38, Folder 18)
      "Applied Mathematics is Bad Mathematics", by Paul Halmos (typescript draft)
      Interview
    - Harary, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 19)
      Extensive bibliography & Curriculum Vitae of Harary
    - Huffman, David, 1991 (Box 38, Folder 20)
      1 profile (SA)
    - Kaczynski (Unibomber), undated (Box 38, Folder 21)
      List of 10 mathematical papers by Caczynski
    - Don Knuth, 1960-2001 (Box 38, Folder 22)
      Interview and many articles
      Many Xmas cards
      Potrzebie system
      Many recreational mathematics references in letters
    - Kraitchik, 1957 (Box 39, Folder 1)
      Obitury (in French)
      Kraitchic, Maurice
    - Kruskal, Martin, 1993-1994 (Box 39, Folder 2)
      2 short articles.
    - Lehrer, Tom, 1997 (Box 39, Folder 3)
      1 article (Math Horizens) with "That's Mathematics" words and music
    - Littlewood, 1978-1996 (Box 39, Folder 4)
      John E. Littlewood
      Several articles & reviews (of "Littlewood's Miscellany")
    - Liberi's Course in RM (& Others), 1974-1984 (Box 39, Folder 5)
      Sevearl outlines for a course in recreational mathematics taught by Albert Liberi in New York
      Moore, Charles
      Liberi, Albert
    - Scott Morris, 1987 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Leo Moser, 1959-1972 (Box 39, Folder 7)
      Correspondence & notes about a proposed book by Moser and MG on mathematical humor.
      Reprints of various Moser problems
      Moser, William
    - John Nash, 1994-2001 (Box 39, Folder 8)
      Several newspaper & magazine articles on Nash, boht his Nobel Prize and teh book about him.
      (Also Kaczynski, the Unibomber, & Erdos books)
    - Pedoe, Dan, 1998 (Box 39, Folder 9)
      1 article (autobiography from College Mathematics Journal)
    - Wade Philpott, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 10)
      2 letters, about his death
    - Pickover, Cliff, 1991-1999 (Box 39, Folder 11)
      Much correspondence between MG and Pickover, about his books & blurbs for them.
      Several book reviews.
    - Poincare, 1999 (Box 39, Folder 12)
      2 book reviews ("Poincare and the Three Body Problem")
      1 biography, photocopied from "Golden Age of Science"
    - Richards, Dana, 1986-1989 (Box 39, Folder 13)
      Curriculum Vita, letter of recommendation (by MG)
      Various articles by Richards
    - Robinson, Julia & Constance Reid, 1992-1996 (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Rogers, Douglas, 1998 (Box 39, Folder 15)
      2 letters from Rogers to MG, & 1 reply
    - Rota, 1997 (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - Rucker, Rudy, 1982-1999 (Box 39, Folder 17)
      Much correspondence
    - Doris Schattschneider, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 18)
      1 picture & short biography
    - Sloane, Neil, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 19)
      2 articles & picture
    - Smale, 1984-1999 (Box 39, Folder 20)
      2 articles & book review
    - Smullyan, Raymond, 1978-1994 (Box 39, Folder 21)
      1 article (Smithsonian) & a little correspondence
    - Steuben, Mike, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 22)
      1 short article (Discover)
    - Ian Stewart, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 23)
      Stewart's prefance to one of his books, and MG introduction
    - Sylvester, 1987-1997 (Box 39, Folder 24)
      3 articles (technical)
      "The Laws of Verse, or Principles of Versification", by J.J.Sylvester, 1870(152 photocopied pages)
    - Tarski, Alfred, 1991-1999 (Box 39, Folder 25)
      Photocopy frm "From Dedekind to Godel" on Tarski
      2 articles (M. INtellegencer)
    - Tukey, John Wilder, 2002 (Box 39, Folder 26)
      1 article (Notices of AMS)
    - Ulam, 1981-1990 (Box 39, Folder 27)
      Interview (2-year CMJ)
      Long biography by Gian-Carlo Rota (1987)
      Couple of articles
    - Van der Waerden, 1997 (Box 39, Folder 28)
      1 article, Notices of AMS
    - Von Neumann, 1964-1998 (Box 39, Folder 29)
      "The Legend of John Von Neumann", by P.R. Halmos, 1973 (reprint)
      Photocopy of "Procedings of Symposia in Pure Mathematics, Vol. 50" on The lLegacy of John von Neumann, 1990 (10 articles)
    - Wang, Hao, 1996 (Box 39, Folder 30)
      1 article, form "Godel '96"
    - Weil, Andre, 1998-1999 (Box 39, Folder 31)
      Obituary
      1 short article
    - Wiener, Norbert, 1995 (Box 39, Folder 32)
    - Wolfram, Stephen, undated (Box 39, Folder 33)
    - Women, 1965-1996 (Box 39, Folder 34)
      Several articles on women in mathematics in general
      Some articles on gender in math
      Sophie Germain article (form Sci. Am.)
      Ruth Lawrence (short, from Time)
  - Mazes, 6 folder(s)
    - Adrian Fisher Mazes, 1986-1999 (Box 22, Folder 10)
      Many articles by and about Adrian Fisher, including several copies of his "Maze News"
      MG introduction for Fisher's book (typescript)
    - Maze Solving Techniques, 1957-1997 (Box 22, Folder 11)
      Chemical method (Science News article)
      Several articles of mathematical methods (2 in French)
      Lee, C.Y.
    - Maze Books, 1970-1989 (Box 22, Folder 12)
      MG report on out-of-print maze books (for Dover)
      Many book reviews and newspaper articles
      Brightfield, Rick
    - Mazes, 1962-2001 (Box 22, Folder 13)
      Lots of mazes!
      MG letter (to Judy-Lynn del Rey) with detailed 3-D maze suggestion
      Friedman (Efjif, Inc)
      Eliot, William
      Pegg, Ed Jr.
    - Outdoor Mazes, 1981-1994 (Box 22, Folder 14)
      Articles, pictures, a little history
    - Bob Abbott, 1988-1995 (Box 22, Folder 15)
      Manuscripts & original drawings of some of Abbott's mazes
  - Mechanical Puzzles, 23 folder(s)
    - Mechanical Puzzles [1 of 3], 1900-1990 (Box 62, Folder 1)
      Many descriptions of mechanical puzzles, mostly in catalogs, and a few magazine articles
      "The Ego Activation Method", by Melvin Weiner, 1980 (reprint), using puzzles as part of psychotheropy
      Strand Magazine articele(1900) on "Chinese Puzzles, Tricks, and Traps, by James Scott
      Yashimoto Cube, Nos. 1,2,3 (descriptions, 1971)
      Polygonzo, 1990 (Howard Jay Fleischer)
      Puzzle World #3, by Dale Overy
      Puzzletts
      Overy, Dale
      Van Delft, Pieter
      Coffin, Stewart
    - Mechanical Puzzles [2 of 3], 1990-1995 (Box 62, Folder 2)
      More puzzle descriptions, in catalogs and articles
      IDI (I.Q. Development Institute, Ewe Meffert, 1990
      Interlocking Puzzles
      World Puzzle Congress (Zagreb, 1991) announcement & program
      Bill Cutler
      Magic Cubes 1991, Christoph Bandelow
      Gantt's Wood Things
      Ishi Press
      General Symmetrics, Inc (Doug Engel)
    - Mechanical Puzzles [3 of 3], 1994-2002 (Box 62, Folder 3)
      Tim's Toy Report, Nos. 2,3,4, 2994
      Various catalogs
      Short articles on: Spinout, Double Dovetail, Japanese Secret Box, Frank Armbrusster, Panex Puzzle, Reversible Nesting Box
      "Ruan Liuqi, The Ingenious Puzzle Craftsman of Suzhou", by Wei Zhang & Peter Rasmussen, 1998, 9pp (booklet)
    - Stewart Coffin [1 of 2], 1970-1977 (Box 62, Folder 4)
      Puzzle News: 1979
      Catalog sheets & Brochures: 1972, 1971, 1977
      Puzzle descriptions: Nova, Seven Woods, Spider Slider, Star, Cuckoo Nest, Locked Nest (with pictureA), Pin Hole
      Puzzle Craft: Vol 1, No. 1; No 2; No 3; No 4; No 5; No 6
    - Stewart Coffin [2 of 2], 1978-1991 (Box 62, Folder 5)
      Puzzle Craft (combined reprint) (1978); also 1981, parts I, II, and Supplement, 1985
      2 fine Woodworking articles (1979, 1984)
      Puzzle descriptions: Six-Piece Burr, Burr #305, Cornucopia
      Catalog sheets: 1981
      "Puzzling World of Polyhedral Dissection", by Stewart Coffin (Rough draft, 1986)
    - Jerry Slocum, 1955-1995 (Box 62, Folder 6)
      Article from Jeux & Strategie (in Frenceh) (photocopy) - about Jerry Slocum
      "Making and Solving Puzzles, by Jerry Slocum, 1955
      Article from Science & Mechanics Magazine
      Compendium of Mechanical Puzzles From Catalogs, by Jerry Slocum, 1977 (Just the intro anf references)
      Several diagrams of various burr puzzles
      Duffy, Mike
    - The LA PUzzle Exhibit, 1984-1986 (Box 62, Folder 7)
      "Puzzles Old and New", at the Craft and Folk Art Museum, 1986-1987
      Printout of orientation panels
      NEH application for grant
    - Rubik's Cube & Other Rubik Items, 1986-1995 (Box 62, Folder 8)
      2 articles on solving (cube and clock)
      Some ads for other items
    - Pyraminx, 1981 (Box 62, Folder 9)
      MG notes on solutions of various patterns
      A 14 page analysis of Pyraminx, nd, possible by Turner-Smith
      Disclosure document to patent office, for Impossible Polyhedron, an invention by James Pearce, with photographs. (Seems to be an Impossiball.)
    - Pentangle Line, 1972-1988 (Box 63, Folder 1)
      A few Pentangle catalogs & sales sheets
    - Orb-It, 1981-1982 (Box 63, Folder 2)
      MG intro to Warnecks book on Orb-It (photocopy)
      Werneck, Tom
    - Tom Ransom Project, 1977-1978 (Box 63, Folder 3)
      Correspondance about possible book
    - T.Q. Rowett, 1984-1998 (Box 63, Folder 4)
      Rowett, Timothy
    - Phoney Baloney, 1970-1971 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - NYC Rec. Math Shop (?), 1939-1980 (Box 63, Folder 6)
      Math-E-Magics - the store where Math is Fun
    - Japanese Puzzles, 1990-1993 (Box 63, Folder 7)
      2 Toyo Glass calendars
      Puzzletopia No. 11 (from Nob Yoshigahara)
      Catalogs from Puzzland, Kikimi, Toyo Glass, Matsuya Ginza, Ishi Press
      Some interviews with Nob Yoshigahara
    - Joel Langer's Wire Knots, 1981-1983 (Box 63, Folder 8)
      Why Knots
      Langer, Joel
    - Sam Cornwall, 1994 (Box 63, Folder 9)
      Photos & stories of his puzzles
      Cornwall, Sam
    - Bill Cutler, 1994-1995 (Box 63, Folder 10)
      Some puzzle designs, and some catalogs
    - Puzzle Cards, undated (Box 63, Folder 11)
      Photocopies
    - Poly-Spheres - Tut's Tomb - Anagog, undated (Box 63, Folder 12)
      MG notes of Tut's Tomb (Mag-Nif)
      Instructions & solutions (photocopy) of Anagog (by Piet Hein)
    - Wire Puzzles, 1991-1993 (Box 63, Folder 13)
      "Analysis of ring Puzzles", by Richard Hess, 4"x5", bound, 1993
      Perry Horton catlog (with drawings), 1991
      Tavern Puzzles
      Photocopy of other mwire puzzles (Richard Hess?)
    - Loony Loop, 1968-1993 (Box 63, Folder 14)
      Puzzle history, and some photocopies of old catalogs with it
      Controversy over who invented it
      Sutton, C.R.
      Armbruster, Frank
      Dyckman, Howard
  - Misc. Math, 12 folder(s)
    - Math Bibliography for NYR, 1987-1990 (Box 66, Folder 10)
      Various versions of bibliography for mathematics books, as wwell as one for computers and artificial intelligence books
    - The "New Math", 1958-1984 (Box 66, Folder 11)
      Lots of articles about the New Math, for and against
      Page, David
    - Strens Collection, 1983-1986 (Box 67, Folder 1)
      (Sallows letters: see Pangram folder, 2/65/7
      Strens, Pascal
    - Sets, Metamath, Etc., 1958-1968 (Box 67, Folder 2)
      Several articles about mathematics itself, and how to organize its parts
      Set theory
    - Foundations (Schools) [1of2], 1961-1989 (Box 67, Folder 3)
      Many technical papers and articles on foundations of mathematics, particularly constructionist (intuitionism), axiomatics (formalism), logicism, etc.
    - Foundations (Schools) [2of2], 1988-1998 (Box 67, Folder 4)
      "Randomness in Arithmetic and the Decline and Fall of Reductionism in Pure Mathematics", by G.J. Chaitin, 1992 (lecture transcript)
    - Nomograms & Triangle-Square Dissection, 1943-1965 (Box 67, Folder 5)
      Some articles on nomogramphs and nomograms
      Dudeneys triangle to square dissection
    - Operations Research, 1957-1971 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Baywood Series, 1978 (Box 67, Folder 7)
      Preliminary plans for books based on Journal of Recreational Mathematics
    - Math & Postage Stamps, 1963-1982 (Box 67, Folder 8)
      Some articles, some pictures, some stamps (with mathematical content)
      Also a couple of articles on stamp errors
    - How to Catch a Lion, 1968-1973 (Box 67, Folder 9)
      2 articles on mathematical methods of big game hunting
    - Pure vs. Applied, 1997 (Box 67, Folder 10)
      Typescript of Golomb's talk "Mathematics Forty Years After Sputnik"
  - Misc. Problems, 35 folder(s)
    - Words & Letters, 1974-1998 (Box 40, Folder 8)
      Kangaroo Words
      Strike-Outs
      Much from Word Ways magazine, and from Games Magazine
      Lots of small word puzzles and games
    - Quickies [1 of 2], 1964-1983 (Box 40, Folder 9)
      Many short problems, from various sources and correspondence.
      3 sets of problems, from Hollard T. Croft: "Problems" (Mostly Geometrical )(1964), "Research Problems" (1967), and "Addenda" (1969)
      Lindberg, Gene
    - Quickies [2 of 2], 1972-1983 (Box 40, Folder 10)
      More short problems.
    - Omitted From Sterling Bk, 1994 (Box 41, Folder 1)
      Proposal for a math puzzle book for children, 5-10 years old. Puzzles all answered by numbers (which would be the next page to read.) Lots of such problems. (Possilbe title: A Mathematical & Magical Puzzle Story.)
    - XEROR - 51 Puzzle Slides, 1974 (Box 41, Folder 2)
      Numbered, not in order
    - Number Items (Dr. Matrix) [1 of 2], 1965-1982 (Box 41, Folder 3)
      Many short number puzzles, problems, and oddities, many used in Dr. Matrix columns
      Nuclear numbers (number of electrons in each shell)
      Anastaplo, George
      Halstead, Tom
      Nagaraj, S.T.
    - Number Items (Dr. Matrix) [2 of 2], 1971-1994 (Box 41, Folder 4)
      Math. Curiosities: Algebraic, Numeric, Oddest odd number (153), squares & cubes, upside down magic squares, cannonball number, etc.
      "The Bard And The Bible", by Allan Slaight, 1966 (typescript)
    - My Favorite Funny Quickies (For 4-Star Puzzler), 1982-1983 (Box 41, Folder 5)
      Several issues of "The 4-Star Puzzles", including one with MG article
    - Quickies From Martin Gardner, undated (Box 41, Folder 6)
      "108 Quickies From Martin Gardner", editied by Andy Liu (from S.A., 1963-1971) (spiral bound booklet)
    - Task Problems, 1968-1998 (Box 41, Folder 7)
      Many ideas fro a task puzzle (story to be written)
      Many task problems.
      Task problem: do some task using unlikely objects
    - Wordles, 1952-1999 (Box 41, Folder 8)
      Word arrangement representing a phrase. Also: "Wacky Wordies", "Word Play", "Phrenetic Phrases", and more.
      Lists of phrases, titles, etc. to be made as wordles.
    - MatheMADics (Wordles), 1967-1999 (Box 41, Folder 9)
      (Wordles of mathematics terms.)
    - Fallacies (All Types), 1958-1996 (Box 41, Folder 10)
      Knapp, Merville
      Dante, William Michael